<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Lassa Fever</string>
    <string name="action_feedback">Feedback</string>
    <string name="action_exit">Exit</string>
    <string name="action_about">About Developers</string>
    <string name="title_activity_lassa_detail">About Lassa</string>
    <string name="title_activity_sign_symptoms">Signs &amp; Symptoms</string>
    <string name="title_activity_cure">Diagnosis</string>
    <string name="title_activity_faq">Prevention</string>
    <string name="title_activity_help">Report Cases</string>
    <string name="help_text">
        "The Governments and Health Organistions are dedicated to provide necessary help in"
        "curing Lassa Fever.\n\n"
        "If you have any information to help Government in curing lassa you can provide us "
        "by calling our help numbers. \n\n"
        "Lassa Fever is a deadly disease, report any incidents to the nearest hospital"
        "and do not stay indoor if you start to see its signs and symptoms\n\n"
        "We dedicated ourselves in curing Lassa throughout Africa.\n\n"
        "<b>#Cure_Lassa\n</b>"
         </string>
    <string name="lassa_detail">
        <b>"\nLassa fever"</b> "is an acute viral illness that occurs in west Africa. The illness"
        " was discovered in 1969 when two missionary nurses died in Nigeria. The virus is named after"
        "the town in Nigeria where the first cases occurred. The virus, a member of the virus family"
        "Arenaviridae, is a single-stranded RNA virus and is zoonotic, or animal-borne.\n\n"
        "Lassa fever is endemic in parts of west Africa including Sierra Leone, Liberia, Guinea "
        "and Nigeria; however, other neighboring countries are also at risk, as the animal vector"
        "for Lassa virus, the multimammate rat (Mastomys natalensis) is distributed"
        "throughout the region. In 2009, the first case from Mali was reported in a traveler living"
        "in southern Mali; Ghana reported its first cases in late 2011. Isolated cases have also"
        "been reported in Côte d’Ivoire and Burkina Faso and there is serologic evidence of Lassa"
        "virus infection in Togo and Benin.\n\n"
        "The number of Lassa virus infections per year in west Africa is estimated at 100,000 to"
        "300,000, with approximately 5,000 deaths."
        "Unfortunately, such estimates are crude, because surveillance for cases of the disease "
        "is not uniformly performed. In some areas of"
        "Sierra Leone and Liberia, it is known that 10 16 of people admitted to hospitals every "
        "year have Lassa fever, which indicates"
        "the serious impact of the disease on the population of this region.\n\n"
        "In 80percent of cases, the disease is asymptomatic, but in the remaining 20percent, it"
        "takes a complicated course. The virus is estimated to be responsible for about"
        "5,000 deaths annually. The fever accounts for up to one­third of deaths in hospitals"
        "within the affected regions and 10percent to 16percent of total cases.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_cases">Incidents Locations</string>
    <string name="title_activity_cases_map">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_case">Case</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
    <string-array name="symbtoms">
        <item>Nausea</item>
        <item>Vomiting (bloody)</item>
        <item>Diarrhea (bloody)</item>
        <item>Stomach ache</item>
        <item>Constipation</item>
        <item>Dysphagia (difficulty swallowing)</item>
        <item>Hepatitis</item>
        <item>Pericarditis</item>
        <item>Hypertension</item>
        <item>Hypotension</item>
        <item>Tachycardia (abnormally high heart rate)</item>
        <item>Cough</item>
        <item>Chest pain</item>
        <item>Dyspnoea</item>
        <item>Pharyngitis</item>
        <item>Pleuritis</item>
        <item>Encephalitis</item>
        <item>Meningitis</item>
        <item>Unilateral or bilateral hearing deficit</item>
        <item>Seizures</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="prevention">
        "\nPrimary transmission of the Lassa virus from its host to humans can be prevented by"
        "avoiding contact with Mastomys rodents, especially in the geographic regions where"
        "outbreaks occur. Putting food away in rodent-proof containers and keeping the home clean"
        "help to discourage rodents from entering homes. Using these rodents as a food source is"
        "not recommended. Trapping in and around homes can help reduce rodent populations; however,"
        "the wide distribution of Mastomys in Africa makes complete control of this rodent"
        "reservoir impractical\n\n"
        "When caring for patients with Lassa fever, further transmission of the disease through "
        "person-to-person contact or nosocomial routes can be avoided by taking preventive precautions"
        "against contact with patient secretions (called VHF isolation precautions or barrier"
        "nursing methods). Such precautions include wearing protective clothing, such as masks, "
        "gloves, gowns, and goggles; using infection control measures, such as complete equipment"
        "sterilization; and isolating infected patients from contact with unprotected persons until"
        "the disease has run its course.\n\n"
        "Further, educating people in high-risk areas about ways to decrease rodent populations"
        "in their homes will aid in the control and prevention of Lassa fever. Other challenges"
        "include developing more rapid diagnostic tests and increasing the availability of the only"
        "known drug treatment, ribavirin. Research is presently under way to develop a vaccine"
        "for Lassa fever.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="text_item_symptom">diarrhea</string>
    <string name="diagnosis">
        "\n<b>Lassa fever</b> is most often diagnosed by using enzyme-linked immunosorbent serologic assays (ELISA), which detect IgM and IgG antibodies as well as Lassa antigen. Reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) can be used in the early stage of disease. The virus itself may be cultured in 7 to 10 days, but this procedure should only be done in a high containment laboratory with good laboratory practices. Immunohistochemistry, performed on formalin-fixed tissue specimens, can be used to make a post-mortem diagnosis.
\n\nRibavirin, an antiviral drug, has been used with success in Lassa fever patients. It has been shown to be most effective when given early in the course of the illness. Patients should also receive supportive care consisting of maintenance of appropriate fluid and electrolyte balance, oxygenation and blood pressure, as well as treatment of any other complicating infections.
\n\nAll persons suspected of Lassa fever infection should be admitted to isolation facilities and their body fluids and
excreta properly disposed of.\n\n
When Lassa fever infects pregnant women late in their third trimester, induction of delivery is necessary for the mother to have a good chance of survival. This is because the virus has an affinity for the placenta and other highly vascular tissues. The fetus has only a one in ten chance of survival no matter what course of action is taken; hence, the focus is always on saving the life of the mother. Following delivery, women should receive the same treatment as other Lassa fever patients.
\n\nWork on a vaccine is continuing, with multiple approaches showing positive results in animal trials.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="select_state">Please choose your State</string>
    <string-array name="state_options">
        <item>Kano</item>
        <item>Jigawa</item>
        <item>Kebbi</item>
        <item>Lagos</item>
        <item>Bauchi</item>
        <item>Bayelsa</item>
        <item>Others</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="title_activity_affected_area">Affected Area</string>
    <string name="title_activity_about_developers">About Developers</string>
    <string name="action_share">Share App</string>
</resources>
